Tauseef Ibne Mamun

tmamun@mtu.edu +1 (857)-574-9931 https://tm-cv-p.herokuapp.com

1812 F Woodmar Drive Houghton, Michigan, 49931

SUMMARY

Graduate student in Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors at Michigan Technological University with a strong programming background and training in both computer science and psychology. Experience in human factors analysis and executing usability studies.

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

MSc. Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

Expected May 2021

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology | Dhaka, Bangladesh

BSc. Computer Science & Engineering

2011 - 2015

2015 - 2019

CGPA: 3.12/4.00

EXPERIENCES

Mighty Egg Technologies | 600 – 56 Temperance Street Toronto, ON M5H 3V5, Canada

Programmer Analyst

Tasks:

- Database Design & API development.
- ERP and Website Development. Mobile App Development (Android).
- Analyzing Client Requirement.
- Software deployment in Amazon Web Service, Digital Ocean, Heroku.

Michigan Technological University, Cognitive and Learning Sciences | Houghton, MI

Research Assistant 2019 – Present

Tasks:

- Improving and designing novel explanation methods for AI systems.
- Developing computational models for Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) systems.

Practicum Student 2020

Supervisor: Robert Hoffman

Task:

Improving and designing collaborative explanation methods for AI systems.

Programming Expertise

Ruby, Python, C, C++, Java, PHP, R, PEBL

CO-CURRICULAR INVOLVEMENT

President (Photography Department) at Notre Dame Nature Study Club
2009 – 2010

General member at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering
Society

General Secretary at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering Society 2013 – 2014

 Vice President at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering Society

Vice President at Bangladeshi Student Association at Michigan Technological University
2020 – 2021

INTERESTS

Photography | App Development | Video and Photo Editing